They needed a hero. They got a villain.
Plankton: The Movie is a family, comedy,
adventure film directed by Dave Needham.
Plankton's tangled love story with his sentient computer wife goes sideways when
she takes a stand — and decides to destroy the world without him.
Plankton / Teen Plankton / Rube / Snorkler (voice), played by Mr. Lawrence.
Karen / All the Karens / Alarm Voice / Stiletto Woman / Old
Lady Cane (voice), played by Jill Talley.
SpongeBob / Random Student / Gary / French
Narrator (voice), played by Tom Kenny.
Patrick / Troop (voice), played by Bill Fagerbakke.
Squidward / Fish Troop / Goofy Goober Employee
(voice), played by Rodger Bumpass.
Sandy (voice), played by Carolyn Lawrence.
Plankton: The Movie is a 2025 American animated musical comedy film based on the
television series SpongeBob SquarePants, created by Stephen Hillenburg.
It was directed by Dave Needham and written by Kaz, Chris Viscardi, and Mr.
Lawrence, based on a story by Lawrence.
It stars the series' regular voice cast, and follows Plankton, whose plans for world
domination are put to a halt when his computer wife, Karen, decides to take charge.
It is the second in a series of SpongeBob character spin-off films for Netflix,
following Saving Bikini Bottom: The Sandy Cheeks Movie in 2024.
The film was originally conceived by Lawrence as a half-hour special,
but was eventually put into development as a feature.
In March 2020, ViacomCBS announced that it would be producing
SpongeBob spin-off films for streaming television.
In June 2024, a spin-off film featuring the character Plankton as its
lead was announced with its creative team attached.
Mahuia Bridgman-Cooper composed the score, and Bret McKenzie, Linda Perry,
Mark Mothersbaugh, and Bob Mothersbaugh wrote original songs.
Prior to its release, the entire film was leaked in
August 2024, as a video upload online.
Plankton: The Movie was officially released on Netflix on March 7, 2025.
The film debuted with 14.3 million views during its premiere weekend, making it the number one overall title on the
streamer's English-language film chart that week, and received generally positive reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of based on cartoon, based on tv
series, 3d animation, hilarious, indifferent.
The tone is lighthearted.